#### Contact

ginahorlu@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/regina-esi-ahorlu-25699259 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

**Critical Care** 

Healthcare

Hospitals

### Languages

**English** 

Spanish

# Certifications CCRN

# Regina Esi Ahorlu

MSN, AGACNP-BC, RN-BC, CCRN at Advanced ICU Care Greater New York City Area

## Summary

Experienced Critical Care Registered Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Critical care Medicine, Adult Liver Transplant, Medical-Surgical patient care services, Healthcare, and Healthcare Management. Strong healthcare services professional with a Master's in Science focused in Adult Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner from New York University.

# Experience

Advanced ICU Care

MSN, AGACNP-BC, RN-BC, CCRN at Advanced ICU Care
September 2017 - Present (2 years 9 months)

St. Louis, Missouri

Critical Care medicine

Northern Westchester Hospital
Critical Care Registered Nurse
August 2015 - January 2018 (2 years 6 months)
Mount Kisco, New York

Good Samaritan Hospital Critical Care Registered Nurse November 2014 - May 2015 (7 months) Suffern, New York

**Emergency Department staff nurse** 

Mount Sinai Medical Center Registered Nurse April 2010 - April 2014 (4 years 1 month) new york, new york

Mount Sinai Medical Center2011 - 2014 Clinical Coordinator, Adult Liver Transplant. • Assists surgical and medical team in retrieval of organs for transplantation using medical instruments. Solicits medical and community groups for organ donors. Coordinates in-hospital services. Communicates with donors, patients, and health team members to ensure comprehensive documentation. Analyzes medical data of organ donors and recipients from medical and social records, physical examination, and consultation with health team. Compares collected data to normal values and correlates. Correlates and summarizes laboratory reports, x rays, and office tests to assist physician in determining medical suitability or procedure. Schedules recipient and donor laboratory tests to determine histocompatibility of blood or tissue of recipient donor. Counsels recipient and donor to alleviate anxieties and assist recipient donor throughout procedure. Assesses progress of patient and offers advice and assistance to patient following transplant. Advises post-operative patients on therapies for managing health after transplant and serves as team member monitor. Performs other related duties.

Mount Sinai Medical Center, 2010 - 2011

Per Diem Nurse in Medical Surgical Specialty Clinic.

Provide medical and surgical needs to patients in an outpatient clinic that covers Orthopedics, Wound, Podiatry, Immunology, Neurology, Rheumatology, Dermatology, ENT, General Surgery (Breast, Plastics, etc), Gastroenterology (Liver, Colonoscopy, Endoscopy, etc), Genitourinary (Renal, etc), Pulmonary, (Asthma, Sarcoidosis, etc), Endocrinology and Hematology Oncology. Responsibilities include documentations, pre and postop preparation, nutrition, elimination, airway maintenance, pain management, discharges, transfers, patient teaching, nursing assessment and interventions, medication administration, and patient safety guidance.

Lenox Hill Hospital
Registered Nurse
June 2009 - October 2011 (2 years 5 months)
New York, New York

Lenox Hill Hospital 2010 -2011

Assistant Nurse Manager (Clinical Coordinator) of the Surgical Intensive Care Unit (SICU) and the Surgical Step-down.

 Responsibilities include daily rounds, hiring of staff, participating in staff appraisals, staff scheduling, supplies, performance improvement projects, bed control (Through Put) client or patient satisfaction review (Press Ganey), encouraging the staff to adhere to company policies and procedures, organizing education or in-service to the staff, to name a few. Also took a full patient assignment if needed in the SICU.

Lenox Hill Hospital. 2009 - 2010

Staff Nurse, Critical Care Float (MICU, SICU, CCU, PCU, PACU, CTICU, and the Step-downs).

• Responsibilities include providing critical care to very unstable patients who require intensive care such as hemodynamic monitoring, medication administration, 12 lead EKG interpretations, mechanical life support; nutrition, elimination, ventilation, wound care, etc, to patients with cardiac, pulmonary, neurological, hematological, renal, gastrointestinal and endocrine crisis.

Orange Regional Medical Center Staff Nurse PD May 2011 - July 2011 (3 months) Middletown, New York

Pioneer Home Care Registered Nurse August 2003 - November 2010 (7 years 4 months) Bronx, New York

Pioneer Homecare Inc. 2003-2010

RN Per Diem

Provided service to both adult and pediatric clients in their homes including patient assessment and interventions, patient teaching, nutrition, elimination, air way maintenance, hygiene, pain management, mechanical life support machines such as, tube feedings, TPN (triple lumen), wound care, ventilators, and medication administration as well as patient safety.

Hurtig-Evans Home Care. 2003-2005 RN Per Diem

• Instructor of medication administration to developmentally disability aides or approved medication administration personnel (AMAP) and staff nurse in group homes. Skills provided include, air way maintenance, nutrition, elimination, hygiene, pain management, nursing assessments and

interventions, catheterization, suctioning, ileostomy care, wound care and medication administration and patient safety.

Metropolitan Hospital Medical Center Registered Nurse June 2004 - July 2009 (5 years 2 months) New York, New York

Metropolitan Hospital Center via White Glove Placement Inc. 2008 – 2009 RN Per Diem -Adult Emergency Room

• Responsibilities included but not limited to sorting out patients based on their level of severity (triage), providing emergency care to patients with varied clinical presentations such as a life threatening case to a sub acute presentation, admission assessments, health promotion and wellness, patient teaching including medications, immunizations, lifestyle changes and perioperative preparations, documentations, pre and post-op preparation, nutrition, elimination, airway maintenance, pain management, discharges, transfers, nursing assessments and interventions, medication administration, and patient safety.

Metropolitan Hospital Center2006-2009

Staff Nurse (RN) in Adult Intensive Care Unit (MICU, CCU and SICU). Responsibilities include providing critical care to very unstable patients who require intensive care such as hemodynamic monitoring, 12 lead EKG interpretations, mechanical life support; nutrition, elimination, ventilation, and wound care, etc, to patients with cardiac, pulmonary, neurological, hematological, renal, gastrointestinal and endocrine crisis. Acted as nurse-incharge in the absence of the head nurse.

White Glove Placement, Inc.2004-2006

RN Per Diem

Provided care to patients requiring medical-surgical care on a Med-Surg unit. Responsibilities included assisting the nurses, RNs, LPNs, support staff and MDs to GO-LIVE with online medication administration as well as nursing documentations with the soft ware Misys.

Metropolitan Hospital Center - Medical-Surgical unit 2003-2006 Staff Nurse (RN) Responsibilities include, charge nurse, admissions, discharges, transfers, patient teachings, nursing assessments and interventions, medication administration, documentations, pre and post-op preparation, wound care, nutrition, elimination, airway maintenance, pain management, and patient safety.

### Education

New York University

Master's in Science, Adult Gerontology Acute Care Nurse

Practitioner · (2012 - 2016)

City University of New York-Herbert H. Lehman College Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2005 - 2007)

Borough of Manhattan Community College Associate in Applied Science, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2000 - 2003)

Instituto Politecnico de Alimentos Ejercito Rebelde, Ciudad de la Havana, Cuba.

Food Technology and Processing · (1990 - 1994)